RIDHAM DAVE

9, Jalsabar Society, Dharamnagar, Sabarmati, Ahmedabad, India 380005 $(+91)7817920140 \diamond ridhamdave5@gmail.com$

EDUCATION

Vishwakarma Government Engineering College, Ahmedabad

July 2016 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer.

CGPA: 9.31

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work for an organization that provides me the opportunity to improve my skills and knowledge to grow along with the organization's objective.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Axiom IO, Ahmedabad

October 2020 - Present

Senior Software Developer

- · Developed Modules for AI-powered recruiter.
- \cdot Worked on Website Clusterisation and Website Categorization.

Pirimid Fintech LLP, Ahmedabad

July 2020 - September 2020

Machine Learning Engineering Intern

- · Worked on Stock Research Report Summarization.
- · Extracted data from the research reports published on the stock from a financial institution.
- · Deployed object detection and OCR pipeline in order to get the data from PDFs.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited, Ahmedabad

Dec 2019 - June 2020

Developer Intern

- · Created an enhanced Rule Engine to address department-specific rules.
- · Worked on configuring and implementing a system that enables the global administrator to create any business rule within any process or workflow of the organization.

Synoptek Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad

Jun 2018 - Jul 2018

Data Scientist Intern

- · Created classification models for e-commerce websites using neural networks.
- · Achieved exposure to classification optimization techniques for further specialization.
- · Worked under an experienced Data Scientist and got deep insights related to optimization algorithms.

Indusa Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad

Jan 2018 - Feb 2018

Android Developer Intern

- · Worked for an enhanced data storage android application enabling customized profile options.
- · Worked on providing restrictions to a user based on roles and policies respectively.
- · Worked on the cloud architecture for data warehousing and storage.

Indusa Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad

Jun 2017 - Jul 2017

Mobile App Development Intern

- · Understood mobile application development and testing on the Xamarin Framework.
- · Participated in designing and developing app screens and its workflow using activities and fragments.
- · Worked on designing, enhancement, bug-fixing, and maintenance of the application.

RESEARCH PROFILE

Student Vice President, Technology and Research, VGEC, GTU Innovation Council

Publication: SDN-based real-time urban traffic analysis in VANET environment, Computer Communications, Volume 149, 2020, Pages 162-175.

Publication: Advances in Single Image Super-Resolution: A Deep Learning Perspective, Proceedings of First International Conference on Computing, Communications, and Cyber-Security (IC4S 2019), Volume 121, 2020

Publication: Automated Machine Learning: The New Wave of Machine Learning, Paper, 2nd International Conference on Innovative Mechanisms for Industry Applications ICIMIA, Pages 205-212, IEEE, 2020

AUTHORED ARTICLES

Industrial Classification of Websites by Machine Learning with hands-on Python, Towards Data Science, Medium (Views: 24K, Published: July 30,2018)

Create your Professional/Educational resume using LaTeX, Towards Data Science, Medium (Views: 9.8K, Published: Sep 24, 2019)

PROJECTS

Real-Time Bus Prediction

This project aims at providing real-time information on public transport buses using a low-cost IoT solution. The prediction engine used for real-time tracking is based on the deep learning approach assembled in an Android App with firebase cloud support.

Data Storage

This android application uploaded on Amazon Appstore can be used to safely store, access, search files, and can manage two different accounts together i.e. private and public, quickly view your content and see file details and activity.

Traffic Analysis of Congestion Spots in VANETs using LSTM

This project is based upon a published work regarding traffic congestion prediction and its analysis in a Vehicular Ad-hoc Network using a central SDN controller. The clustering models and the analysis models run on a hybrid K-means algorithm and LSTM model respectively.

Industrial Classification of Websites using Machine Learning and Data Scraping

The project was about Industrial Website Extraction to classify the companies based on the items the website sold or maintained, into categories. The required tools for the task include NLTK, Tensorflow, and Beautiful Soup.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages C, C++, Python, Java-J2EE, C#
Technologies MVC, Serverless, Docker Hosting, Latex

Tools Keras, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn, Android Studio, Anaconda, Kile

Databases MySql, Oracle, Sqlite, NoSql, MongoDb, DynamoDb

Cloud Technologies Firebase, AWS, Google Cloud

Version Control Github, GitLab

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded Certificate of Excellence for being Top Ranker 2017 in Devang Mehta IT awards.

Project 'Real-Time Bus Prediction in City Transport' won Best Project under Multi-Disciplinary category under SSIP, Government of Gujarat

Received Scholarship For Higher Education(She) Component Under Inspire Scheme worth INR 4,00,000

Achieved A Grade in Diploma in Multilingual Computer Programming from C-DAC, GIST

First Runners up in Tic-Tech-Toe Hackathon organized by IEEE, Gujarat at DA-IICT, Gandhinagar for Project 'Edu.io' in January 2018

Won First Prize in Zonal C quiz Competition Organized by Silver Oak Institute, Ahmedabad.

Intel Edge AI Scholarship Winner, 2019-2020, Udacity

EXTRA-CIRRUCULAR

Co-Organized "Vishwahack 1.0" - a National hackathon at VGEC under GTU Central TechFest, 2018.

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won the zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project Youth Brigade INVINCIBLE- The NGO

Attended international conference on Computing, Communications, and Cyber-Security(IC4S-2019), Chandigarh